export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2002 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The payment of bride wealth by the family of the groom signifies",
A: "the social status of the woman’s family",
B: "a token of appreciation to the woman’s family",
C: "a healthy relationship existing between the two families",
D: "the acceptance of the marriage by both families",
answer: "D. the acceptance of the marriage by both families",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The breakdown of traditional family system is the result of",
A: "high cost of living",
B: "assisting needy family members",
C: "increasing religious activities",
D: "urban development",
answer: "D. urban development",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Which of the following factors account for the increasing rate of divorce in Ghana?  \nI.	Growth of individualism  \nII.	Changing status of women  \nIII.	Financial independence of women  \nIV.	Compatibility of interest of couples",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I,II and III only",
D: "I,III and IV only",
answer: "D. I, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Which of the following statements is true about the extended family?",
A: "Its main function is procreation",
B: "lt fosters co-operation between parents and children",
C: "It is the first agent of socialization",
D: "It leads to land fragmentation",
answer: "C. It is the first agent of socialization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. The spread of HIV/AlDS can be limited through",
A: "discouraging promiscuity",
B: "separating AIDS patients from others",
C: "conducting frequent AIDS tests",
D: "having regular vaccination",
answer: "A. discouraging promiscuity",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. One of the social consequences of teenage pregnancy is",
A: "malnutrition of the child",
B: "neglect by family members",
C: "admiration by peers",
D: "increase in school drop-out rate",
answer: "A. malnutrition of the child",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The female reproductive organ which provides the environment for the development for",
A: "vagina",
B: "cervix",
C: "ovary",
D: "uterus",
answer: "D. uterus",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Parenthood starts",
A: "immediately pregnancy is confirmed",
B: "when a couple decides to adopt a child",
C: "when a person reaches the stage of puberty",
D: "immediately after marriage",
answer: "A. immediately pregnancy is confirmed",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Responsible parenting behaviours are manifested when parents",
A: "fail to show affection for their children",
B: "continue to correct their children",
C: "find it difficult to meet the social needs of their children",
D: "neglect their children because of survival needs",
answer: "B. continue to correct their children",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One of the befits of rapid population growth is the",
A: "determination of the size of a country",
B: "creation of markets for goods and services",
C: "establishment of more industries",
D: "development of slums",
answer: "B. creation of markets for goods and services",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. The interstate Succession Law (PNDC Law 111) was enacted to",
A: "avoid unfair treatment to the wife of a deceased",
B: "encourage the family to take proper control of all assets of the deceased",
C: "enable only the children of the deceased to take all assets",
D: "share all the assets and liabilities of a deceased between the family and the state",
answer: "A. avoid unfair treatment to the wife and children of a deceased",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. The best method of reducing the high rate of population growth in Ghana is",
A: "increasing the marital age",
B: "creating more jobs",
C: "practicing family planning",
D: "reducing income inequalities",
answer: "C. practicing family planning",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. An example of natural right is the right to",
A: "personal poverty",
B: "adequate wages",
C: "medical care",
D: "free education",
answer: "A. personal property",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. The individual should obey the laws of the state because he or she",
A: "enjoys free basic education",
B: "buys certain commodities at subsidized cost",
C: "is protected by the state",
D: "humours his or her tax obligation",
answer: "C. is protected by the state",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. A person who fails to appreciate himself or herself has a",
A: "highly respectable family background",
B: "very poor self-image",
C: "low emotional background",
D: "poor physical structure",
answer: "B. very poor self-image",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. Under which condition can certain rights of the citizens be suspended",
A: "when the judiciary demands it",
B: "when an important person dies",
C: "under a state of emergency",
D: "during the celebration of a national anniversary",
answer: "C. Under a state of emergency",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Low productivity in the public sector in Ghana is the result of",
A: "bureaucratic bottlenecks",
B: "introduction of computers",
C: "formation of labour unions",
D: "availability incentives",
answer: "A. bureaucratic bottlenecks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. In traditional farming, the main reason for burning the bush after clearing is that",
A: "weeds are prevented from growing",
B: "farmers are too lazy to weed",
C: "wild animals are driven away",
D: "ashes act as potash to fertilize the soil",
answer: "D. ashes act as potash to fertilize the soil",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. The low level of science and technology in Ghana can be attributed mainly to",
A: "the superstitious beliefs of the people",
B: "peoples disregard for science and technology",
C: "poor foundation for the development of science and technology",
D: "poor teaching of science at the basic level",
answer: "D. poor teaching of science at the basic level",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. All national flags fly at half-mast when there is a",
A: "referendum",
B: "state mourning",
C: "national anniversary",
D: "state emergency",
answer: "B. state mourning",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Socialization is important to society because",
A: "it ensures the continuity of society",
B: "it emphasizes the acquisition of knowledge in schools",
C: "it is the essential link between the individual and society",
D: "it enables the individual to learn the culture of the society",
answer: "A. it ensures the continuity of society",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. The mechanisms of social control are meant to",
A: "encourage positive behaviour at the work place",
B: "ensure conformity to laws",
C: "discourage adolescent chastity",
D: "promote responsible parenting",
answer: "B. ensure conformity to laws",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. One main social reason for people living together in groups is",
A: "the joy of friendship",
B: "for the welfare of the community",
C: "for safety and defence",
D: "to maintain law and order",
answer: "C. for safety and defence",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The most important aim of formal education is to",
A: "assist the individual to ensure better employment",
B: "acquire higher academic excellence",
C: "acquire technical skills",
D: "make the individual fit well into the society",
answer: "D. make the individual fit well into the society",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. A highly cherished virtue in the traditional society is",
A: "chastity before marriage",
B: "late pregnancy",
C: "boasting of one’s wealth",
D: "having a lot of assets",
answer: "A. chastity before marriage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. Festivals are occasions for",
A: "tribal warfare",
B: "family re-union",
C: "ritual murder",
D: "child naming",
answer: "B. family re-union",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The most important element in human behaviour is",
A: "wealth",
B: "religion",
C: "culture",
D: "politics",
answer: "C. culture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. The behaviors and ideas that are commonly shared by citizens of a country is referred to as",
A: "nationality",
B: "patriotism",
C: "national pledge",
D: "national identity",
answer: "D. national identity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Military governments rule by",
A: "constitution",
B: "conventions",
C: "decrees",
D: "veto",
answer: "C. decrees",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Protection of individual rights is the function of the",
A: "Legislature",
B: "Executive",
C: "Judiciary",
D: "Military",
answer: "C. Judiciary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Democracy refers to a government",
A: "of the best citizens in a nation",
B: "of traditional rulers",
C: "by the majority of the people",
D: "by the minority of the people",
answer: "C. by the majority of the people",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. The sovereignty of a state is violated when the country",
A: "is under foreign invasion",
B: "has strong military force",
C: "practices multi party system",
D: "is under military rule",
answer: "A. is under foreign invasion",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Which of the following explains why countries adopt a written constitution?  \nI. To act as a check on the holders of political power  \nlI. To outline clearly the functions of the various institutions of government  \nIII.	To publish the manifesto of the ruling party  \nIV.	To divide the powers of government among the various organs of government",
A: "I and II only",
B: "III and IV only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, II and IV only",
answer: "D. I, II and IV only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. Provisions in a constitution that cannot be easily amended are known as",
A: "Bills or Rights",
B: "Entrenched Clauses",
C: "Human Rights",
D: "Dills of Liberties",
answer: "B. Entrenched Clauses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following leadership styles grants complete freedom to followers?",
A: "Paternalistic",
B: "Laissez-faire",
C: "Autocratic",
D: "Democratic",
answer: "B. Laissez-faire",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. Trade between countries may lead to",
A: "decrease in export earnings",
B: "increase in the value of imports",
C: "efficient use of resources",
D: "fall in the output of goods and services",
answer: "C. efficient use of resources",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. The Economic Commission of Africa (ECA) is an agency of the",
A: "United Nations Organization (U.N.O.)",
B: "Non-Aligned Movement (N.A.M.)",
C: "Commonwealth",
D: "World Trade Union (W.T.U.)",
answer: "A. United Nations Organization (U",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. The term greenhouse effect refers to",
A: "decreasing atmospheric humidity",
B: "decreasing atmospheric pressure",
C: "increasing atmospheric temperature",
D: "increasing amount of rainfall",
answer: "C. increasing atmospheric temperature",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. Burning of vegetation contributes to global warming through the release of",
A: "sulphur dioxide",
B: "hydrogen oxide",
C: "nitric oxide",
D: "carbon dioxide",
answer: "D. carbon dioxide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. The high rate of deforestation in Ghana is partly due TP",
A: "increase in livestock rearing",
B: "use of machines in farming",
C: "construction of roads",
D: "high dependence on fuel wood",
answer: "D. high dependence on fuel wood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. When a nation’s human resource development is based on a mere acquisition of knowledge, then",
A: "skilled personnel are produced",
B: "many school leavers become unemployable",
C: "the country catches up with the developed nations",
D: "the progress of the nation is not affected",
answer: "B. many school leavers become unemployable",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. An abundant labour force is a major resource, provided it is",
A: "well trained",
B: "highly remunerated",
C: "fairly young",
D: "well-nourished",
answer: "A. well trained",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Ghana’s natural resources have not been sufficiently exploited mainly because of",
A: "insufficient job opportunities",
B: "inadequate technical know-bow",
C: "adequate capital",
D: "traditional beliefs",
answer: "B. inadequate technical know-how",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. The mainstay of Ghana’s economy is",
A: "mining",
B: "tourism",
C: "agriculture",
D: "manufacturing",
answer: "C. agriculture",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The main function of the entrepreneur is",
A: "combining factors of production",
B: "giving incentives lo employees",
C: "providing finances for the enterprise",
D: "recruiting labour for the enterprise",
answer: "A. combining factors of production",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. Development in the rural areas has lagged behind that of the urban centres mainly because· of",
A: "insufficient capital",
B: "poor communication network",
C: "inadequate natural resources",
D: "superstitious beliefs",
answer: "A. insufficient capital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The low standard of living in developing countries is the result of",
A: "high savings",
B: "high dependency ratio",
C: "high mortality rate",
D: "high literacy",
answer: "B. high dependency ratio",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. One advantage of the use of indigenous technology is that it is",
A: "always free",
B: "highly profitable",
C: "less expensive",
D: "easily amended",
answer: "C. less expensive",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. Government policies are implemented at the local government levels by",
A: "Presiding Members",
B: "District Chief Executives",
C: "Sector Ministers",
D: "Co-ordinating Directors",
answer: "B. District Chief Executives",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Which of the following behaviors should be encouraged at the work place?  \nI.	Sense of duty and loyalty \nII.	Hardwork and pilfering  \nIII.	Updated skills and loitering  \nIV.	Honesty and innovation",
A: "I and III only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "II, III and IV only",
D: "I, II and III only",
answer: "B. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},



]